Hi everybody. I'm John Kiriakou. Welcome
back to another Q&A session here on Deep
Focus.
Love getting the all the questions.
Thank you for reaching out. I apologize
in advance that we can't get to all of
them just because we're we're
overwhelmed by them, but we're trying to
take a sampling from from across the
board. So, I'd like to start with with
Dirty d e r r t y Dirty 66. Hey John,
first and foremost, I want to say thank
you for the things that you've done and
continue to do for the American people
and for standing up for truth and the
rule of law even at great personal cost
to yourself. Thank you for that. Knowing
what you know now about government
agencies and the influence of foreign
powers in our government,
if you were to wake up tomorrow at 25
years old, would you join a government
agency again?
Or do you feel that they have gone too
far?
Are there any organizations, nonprofits,
et cetera that you know of that work for
the good of the American people and the
interests of the US as a whole that you
would recommend fellow patriots getting
involved with? Thank you very much for
your time and hope to see you pardoned
soon. Thank you.
Those are those are tough
questions.
You know, and I I gen- I generally
always say,
"No, I'm a realist. The only way you can
change the CIA is to do it from the
inside. Blah blah blah."
I think I've come around to the point of
view that I should have gone to film
school.
You know, I feel like
I feel like
I've worked so hard,
the people around me have worked so
hard, my friends and my former
colleagues have worked so hard to ensure
the rule of law.
And then we, you know, invade Iran.
We kidnap Maduro.
We threaten to squeeze the life right
out of Cuba. There is no rule of law.
So, it's disheartening. You also caught
me on kind of a bad day. I'm I'm in a
bad mood today.
Been getting a lot of death threats,
which I think
I should actually see as a good thing.
The message is getting out there. Thanks
to you, we are up to 206,000
subscribers.
Because of you.
And I think that's beginning to frighten
some people, some important people
who hide behind the anonymity of Google
Voice
and uh
and untraceable VPN emails to uh make
threats that they can't carry out. But
anyway,
yeah, I think maybe I should have gone
to film school.
With that said,
I do believe that these deep state
agencies like the CIA, NSA, FBI, DIA,
DARPA,
I believe they have they are too far
gone.
I'm not sure that they can be reformed
anymore. I think probably that they
can't be reformed. And are there any
organizations, nonprofits that I know of
that work for the good of the American
people? That's a tough one. I'm
especially close to Code Pink, the the
anti-war group. They've been very, very
good to me over the years, and I know
everybody in Code Pink. They are
beautiful people
who who have dedicated their lives to
stopping war.
And and dedicated their lives to support
human rights.
But, you know, in terms of
NGOs like
think tanks, for example, um
you know, the National Endowment for
Democracy,
uh the DNC and RNC, international
organizations, even my old beloved
AFL-CIO.
They're all tied to the deep state.
And so, who do you trust? I trust Code
Pink.
Um, I'd have to really give it some very
serious thought to be able to tell you
who else
I trust. Thank you for that.
Bull says, "Hi John, massive respect and
thank you
to you and your work. I have one
question. Do you think we are in World
War or the beginning of World War I
think we're on the precipice of World
War III.
You know, firing a couple of rockets at
Iran is one thing.
But
but sending ground troops is an entirely
different thing.
And then
it should surprise no one that the
Russians are giving the Iranians
targeting data, just like we gave the
Ukrainians targeting data, just like the
Russians gave the North Vietnamese
targeting data.
This is what superpowers do.
If we intend to put boots on the ground
um
then I think World War III would be
something that we ought to be actively
worried about.
And it looks like we're putting boots on
the ground. It's one thing to take Kharg
Island.
It's one thing to
take the Greater and Lesser Tunb Islands
and give them back to Sharjah in the
United Arab Emirates. It's an entirely
different thing to actually launch a
land invasion of
Iran. I can't imagine anything so stupid
so short-sighted so criminally negligent
as
an actual ground invasion of Iran. These
attacks are bad enough. They're crimes
against humanity and war crimes.
Um
and you know, we should take a message
from the rest of the world.
Just today, we're recording this on
Monday morning.
Earlier this morning, the government of
Spain banned
overflight clearance for all American
military aircraft. The The Spanish won't
even even let us fly over Spanish
territory
on our way to uh
to Iran.
Good for them.
That's the right thing to do. I wouldn't
be surprised if if other countries soon
follow.
Like Ireland, for example. Maybe even
Italy.
So,
yeah, I think we're I think we're at the
precipice. It's not too late to turn
back, but we're in an exceedingly
dangerous
time right now.
NRF Futures Past says, "Hi John, I'm a
huge fan and I would love to meet you
one day as you have recently become one
of my heroes. Thank you, and I look up
to you." Appreciate that very much.
I sure hope you get that well-deserved
pardon. I have two questions. The first
of which is, "What is your opinion about
the A-10 Warthog being used against
Iranian fast boats in the Strait of
Hormuz?" Great question.
"Do you think that will make any
difference in reopening the strait or is
it just theatrics to attempt to show
some level of control over the strait?
Also, on a less serious note, Star Wars
or Star Trek?" Ha, that's an easy one.
"Personally, I'm a huge Star Wars nerd,
so I'd love to know if you like either
one. Again, you are not only my hero,
but an American hero, and thank you for
your fight to shed light on the truth
for the American people. Thank you very,
very much for that."
Um
the A-10 Warthog is one of the most
beloved
planes that the US has ever produced,
and I mean from the Wright brothers
onward.
The A-10 is easy to handle. It's easy to
maneuver, and it is specifically
designed for close-in combat.
The Air Force was apoplectic when the
Pentagon announced that it was going to
phase out the A-10 Warthog because
everybody loves the Warthog. Everybody.
Well, now they're bringing it back.
And they're bringing it back because
it is effective against Iranian fast
boats. You know, the United States
historically has had real trouble
defending against Iranian fast boats in
the Strait of Hormuz. The fast boats are
run by the IRGC.
And so
the people that are that are manning
them are highly trained. They're
perfectly happy to open fire and they
routinely will grab
boats or ships that stray into Iranian
waters and force them back into port
into Iran and hold them
until they can, you know, negotiate a
release.
The A-10
shows that we're we're in the business
of killing.
And so if anything is going to open the
Strait of Hormuz
or at least give give the United States
the chance to keep the Strait open, it's
going to be the A-10 Warthog. I'm not
saying that's a good thing.
I'm saying that it's the reality that we
find ourselves in today.
So, Star Wars or Star Trek?
I love them both, but definitely Star
Trek. In fact, I DVR Star Trek every
single day.
I got I got the chance to meet William
Shatner
and God, I just love the thing. Um, I
was invited to lunch at at Leonard
Nimoy's house. He had just died, but his
wife invited me over to lunch.
Wonderful lunch. It was just four of us.
And um
it took all my energy not to talk about
Star Trek. She wanted to talk about
civil rights, which is great. Mrs.
Nimoy. Um
but man, I I wish Leonard had been
alive. I would love to have, you know,
told him live long and prosper.
In another life, maybe. Thanks for those
questions.
Caesar's Ghost, good to hear from you
again.
Caesar's Ghost says, "Your channel has
to be one of the best channels to ever
hit YouTube. Hey, thank you. Congrats
Congratulations on the rising success."
I appreciate it. "I have a question if
you have the chance to answer. I know
that Stewart Copeland's father
yes, was one of the founders of the CIA.
Me being a big The Police fan, I'm
wondering if the CIA has used bands as a
way to get into countries or if any
musicians
have ever been used as assets?" That is
a great question. I I can't answer the
last question, have any musicians ever
been used as assets? I don't know the
answer, but even if I did, that would be
one of those sources and methods things
that I can't answer.
The CIA
has just begun declassifying
35, 40, 50-year-old information on the
use of authors and writers, not
journalists, but authors, um
operationally, especially during the
Cold War in the fight against the Soviet
Union. Doctor Zhivago is the most famous
story. It's been extensively reported on
and it's fascinating.
Um Stewart Copeland's dad Stewart
Copeland of The Police, the band The
Police from the from the '80s and '90s.
Uh Stewart Copeland's dad was a senior
intelligence service member of the CIA,
somebody who was widely respected and
highly accomplished. Um it's funny to me
that not only did his son become a
musician, but became a great musician
and a wildly successful.
I uh like I say, I don't know if the CIA
has used bands in this way.
USIA
has used bands, obviously in this way,
because they're great
propaganda mechanisms, right? If if it's
there's an Iron Curtain and and people
on the street love American rock and
roll, then by God, you send rock bands
through USIA, the US Information Agency.
Um, we don't do that anymore because we
don't have the budget for it. But even
in the 90s, when I was stationed in
Bahrain,
we used to have like top-level
jazz musicians, soul singers uh make
these worldwide tours or regional tours
um
just to expose locals to American
culture and music, and the propaganda
value was astronomical.
Before I go on to the next question, uh
I want to read an ad from one of our
sponsors. The biggest wealth transfer in
American history could be coming. The
only question is which side of it you'll
be on.
Here's what's happening. For 90 years,
the US government has valued its gold
reserves at a price set in 1973
by Richard Nixon. Gold now trades at
record highs. The gap between the
official number and the real number is
over a trillion dollars. That gap has to
close eventually.
President Trump has the legal authority
to close it with a single executive
order, the same authority that FDR used
in 1934 to revalue gold overnight. Back
then, it transferred billions of dollars
in wealth to the government at citizens'
expense.
This time, it could go the other way,
but only for people who are positioned
before the announcement. Central banks
already see this coming. China, Russia,
India, Poland
record gold purchases three years
running. They're not waiting to find out
what happens. They're preparing and
they're buying up gold.
I have partnered with American
Alternative Assets to release a free
report called The Great Gold Reset. It
breaks down exactly what Trump could do,
why central banks are moving now, and
how to position your retirement before
the window closes. So, go to
johnlovesgold.com
to get your free copy. That is
or you can call toll-free 1-888-GOLD-053
and they'll mail you one.
Mizuki says, "Hey John, big fan from
Jacksonville, Florida. Two questions. Do
you have any predictions on what the
outcome will be with the ongoing
Ukrainian war? And does the CIA use much
air travel of their own or do they
typically hitch rides with other
branches of the military? Thanks for
everything you've done and Godspeed on
your pardon and pension." Thank you.
Great questions.
The Ukraine question is easier to
answer. The Ukrainians have lost the
war.
I mean, that's the consensus among
American um Russia scholars. The
Ukrainians have lost the war. They're
holding on because the United States and
the European Union have supplied them
with enough weapons and weapon systems
in order to hold on, but they're
gradually losing more and more territory
and that's why the Russians won't engage
in peace talks.
They don't need to engage in peace talks
because they're winning.
Of course, it would be to the United
States benefit
for there to be peace talks and to get
this thing done. The bottom line is it
appears that the Ukrainians are going to
have to concede territory. This is
something that many of us said way back
when the war first began
that the Ukrainians are going to lose
Donetsk,
Luhansk, they're going to have to
they're going to have to concede the
Crimea
and um
and just hope that losses don't get any
worse than that.
On the on the other side, the Russians
are going to have to concede that the
Ukrainians are going to get fast-tracked
into the European Union. I doubt that
Ukraine will become a member of NATO.
That's what this war's been about from
the beginning, but European Union, yes.
And it would just take the stroke of a
pen to give Ukraine what's called major
non-NATO status.
Um
Australia's not in NATO. South Korea,
Japan are not in NATO, right? And so
neither is Saudi Arabia, the UAE,
Bahrain aren't in NATO.
Well, we just treat Ukraine the same
way.
It's de facto NATO. I think that's
what's going to what's going to happen.
Does the CIA CIA use much air travel of
their own?
Well, as I'm sure you imagine um the CIA
CIA employees fly
tens of millions of air miles a year.
The CIA used to have its own jet. I was
only on it once.
But um they did away with that jet in
the 1990s during uh a cost-cutting
period during the Clinton
administration. When I say did away with
it, they gave it to the FBI because the
FBI needed it to shuttle
prisoners from the you know, 10 most
wanted list from point A to point B. And
then anytime we needed the jet
operationally, we would just call the
FBI and say, "Hey, we need the jet." And
then they would loan it to us.
Otherwise, CIA officers always fly
commercial. Unless you're involved in
some kind of a joint operation with the
military or
for example, when I was in Afghanistan
rather than fly commercial and risk, you
know, you can't fly Camair cuz it goes
through Tehran, but we would fly Air
India or Pakistan Airways, PIA.
It was better just to hitch a ride with
Well, the last two rides I hitched in
Afghanistan were with the North Dakota
Air National Guard and the Missouri Air
National National Guard and they would
fly us straight to Dubai and then we
would just get on a United flight from
Dubai. So, yeah, you hitch a ride when
you're in a war zone. That's easy
enough. Uh but most of the time, 99% of
the time, you're going to go commercial.
Carlos Sotero says, "Hi John, I'm a big
fan of your work and what you stand
for." Thank you, Carlos. I truly hope
that you get that pardon and your
pension. Thank you.
You've spoken extensively about Israel
as an intelligence threat to the US, but
I haven't heard you say much about Cuba
in the interviews and clips I've
watched. I'm Bolivian and in Latin
America, Cuban intelligence is often
seen as the most effective service in
the region.
How is Cuban intelligence regarded
inside the CIA? Was it considered
especially capable? Any stories that
illustrate why it earned that
reputation? I'm going to go one farther.
Uh Carlos,
the Cuban intelligence service is one of
the best on the planet.
I can tell you
that of all the Cubans
ever recruited by the CIA,
literally every one of them turned out
to be a double agent, a double agent
working for the Cuban intelligence
service. They are brilliant.
They're so good at what they do,
but we don't hear about them because
they are defensive in nature.
Their job is to protect Cuba.
They're not plotting, you know,
invasions of Iran or invasions of Iraq
or invasions of Afghanistan or military
operations in Somalia or Libya or Syria.
They're just focused on protecting Cuba.
And they're smart
and they're accomplished and they were
trained by the KGB
and they're just really, really good at
what they do.
Especially cap- especially capable is
the term you used? Absolutely, yes.
Jay says, "Hi John, I really enjoy your
content and how you explain the deeper
political dynamics of the Middle East.
You often share great stories about
Iraq, Pakistan, and Saudi Arabia. I'm
half Moroccan, so I'm especially
interested in Morocco's history and
political positioning.
Morocco was the first country to
recognize the United States. That's
absolutely true.
And I find it fascinating how the
Moroccan monarchy has made maintained
strong relationships with US presidents
over the years. I'd really love your
perspective as an expert. Can you share
some lesser-known stories or
behind-the-scenes anecdotes about
Morocco's politics and its relationships
with the US and other Arab countries,
especially moments or stories that
aren't widely known and really show how
Morocco operates between different
powers? I feel like Morocco doesn't get
talked about enough. So, it would be
great to hear you dive into it more in
your podcast. Wishing you all the best.
Hope you get your pardon.
Thank you, buddy. Thanks for that. I
want to tell you that there are very few
countries in the world that are as
beloved
at the CIA and at the State Department
as Morocco.
And it's not just Morocco as a country.
It's the Moroccan people.
And it's especially the Moroccan
leadership.
King Mohammed
is so highly respected.
I would put King Mohammed up there with
King Abdullah of uh of Jordan
as people who are who are beloved
inside the US government for the wisdom
of their leadership.
You are not kidding when you say that
Moroccan kings historically
Moroccan kings have had very close
relationships with American presidents.
Morocco is a country of outsized
importance.
Uh it's
population would have you think, well,
you know, it's a smallish country. It's
kind of located off on the fringe on the
on the northwestern coast of Africa.
Makes no difference.
Everybody loves the Moroccans.
Everybody.
Um I had occasion a couple of times to
work with the Moroccan uh government and
the Moroccan intelligence service.
And I'll tell you really all we wanted
to do is hurry up and get the work done
so we could go out and have dinner
together afterwards.
Seriously, we all loved each other.
They're smart.
They operate under the radar.
They are
poly-linguistic
speaking a bunch of different languages
whether it's English or Arabic or French
or Berber or you name it.
Um
It was I'm genuinely always my pleasure
to work with Morocco. And you know,
funny thing is I never went to Morocco
until 20
18 was the first time I went to Morocco.
And and I went as a tourist. You know,
we we've got these direct flights now
from Baltimore. They take like 4 hours
and you're there. And it's awesome and
people are friendly and the food is
magnificent
and it's exotic if you're an American.
You can go to the souk and go shopping.
I went from like Casablanca to Rabat to
Marrakech. It was just
it was magnificent. And I said to to my
partner the other day, I said, "Hey, you
want to go to Morocco?"
I I haven't been to Morocco since 2018.
She was like, "I I just went to Morocco
2021. Let's go someplace different.
We'll go to Morocco next time."
But yeah, man, it's
you got a great country there.
Really great.
Ketab Shah says, "Hi John. Love your
content. I've seen all of your podcasts
and love hearing your stories." Thank
you, buddy.
I was wondering if you have ever visited
India. Oh, yes.
And if so, do you have any stories about
it? Recently there has been a very
popular movie Dorundar about terrorism
within Pakistan. I was just talking to
an Indian guy about this last night.
Uh and it's in Pakistan's involvement in
the attacks in India. Highly suggest
watching. I'm told that it's on Netflix.
So, we were talking about this yesterday
at a at a Baltimore Orioles baseball
game, and I said, I'm I'm going to
definitely check it out.
Also,
I was wondering if you have any insights
into the Pakistan Balochistan conflict.
Oh, I do. Some people are saying
Pakistan will split up due to all the
conflicts going on in that country and
for the Baloch people fighting for their
independence, and only the Punjab
province will remain to be Pakistan.
Wishing you the best of luck on your
pardon and expressing my support for
Kyriakos
Kyriakos president. Joy28, thank you,
but no, thank you. Um, thank you for
those outstanding questions. First of
all, Durandar,
if it's as great as my buddy says it is,
yeah, I'm going to check it out. I'm
going to check it out like in the next
day or two.
Uh,
every time I talk about Pakistan, I get
death threats, and I have to tell you,
this week has been like a banner week
for death threats.
I got 72 calls this morning
from the same guy
saying he's going to spread my brains
all over the streets.
Anyway, every time I mention Pakistan,
the death threats heap on. So, I'm going
to be careful here. What I will say is,
um,
Pakistani supported terrorism in India
is well documented.
The The Mumbai attacks didn't invent
themselves.
Somebody had to train those terrorists.
Somebody had to arm those terrorists.
Somebody had to finance those
terrorists.
And we all know it was it was Pakistan.
So, there's that.
This Balochistan situation is very
interesting to me.
I'll be honest with you, I don't like
Balochistan
at all.
It's dangerous. It's ugly. It's dry, and
the food is bad.
Like all the things that are important
to me.
There's this terrorist group called the
Balochistan Liberation Army.
Their policy is just kill everybody.
Everybody in a uniform. Kill every
Pakistani cop. Kill every Pakistani ISI
officer. Go out in the streets
and kill people who support the cops and
the ISI. And then you go out later and
you kill people who remind you of the
people who you killed earlier.
That's not a policy.
You're just going to get destroyed.
So, I don't think that this is going to
result in the breakup of Pakistan. I
think what's going to happen is
is the Pakistani central government is
going to get tired of people killing
their cops and killing their soldiers
and killing their ISI officers and we're
going to see a major military move in
Balochistan. And where are the Balochis
going to run?
They're going to run to Iran?
They're going to run to southern
Afghanistan?
Best of luck. Let me know how that works
out.
So,
no, I think we're going to get to the
point soon where heads are going to
roll.
And I mean that they're literally
going to roll. It's not going to be a a
pretty sight.
And thank you for your lovely comments.
Want to take another short break and and
give you an ad from our our second
sponsor. If there's one thing that we've
learned over the last few years, it is
that access to medication can change
quickly depending on the politics,
regulation, and corporate influence.
That is why it's important to have a
pharmacy that focuses on access and
transparency, not on bureaucracy.
This is the reason why people are
turning to All Family Pharmacy. Instead
of scheduling doctor visits, sitting in
a waiting room, and dealing with
insurance approvals, the entire process
is handled online. You can choose the
medications you need on their website,
fill out a short medical form, and a
licensed doctor reviews your request. If
appropriate, they'll provide the
prescription, and then the order ships
directly to your door.
It's a simple way to keep essential
medications on hand like antibiotics,
antivirals, ivermectin, mebendazole,
NAD+ and more than 400 other
prescription medications that people
rely on every day. So, prepare now
before you need it in the future. Visit
allfamilypharmacy.com/john
and use promo code John10, John and the
number 10 to save 10% on your next
order.
Spider
Please, Spider, don't ever apologize for
something like that. Thank you for your
generosity. Spider says,
"I'm a hacker since I was a child and I
currently work as a red teamer. For
those who don't know what that means, I
hack companies with their approval to
identify points of failure and to help
them fix it. I would like to know, what
are your thoughts on Brazilian
intelligence? Even if you don't have
direct experience with interacting with
them, any information would be valuable
for us since we have very, and I mean
it, very little knowledge about them.
Besides that, what do you think about
the cyber operations happening around
the world? We know governments use
hackers to access digital information
including the USA, but what do you think
about the ethics of it? What should be
the limits of government hackers,
contractors, or intelligence agents
directly in the greater scheme of things
in espionage?
I love your show and podcast. Praying to
the gods that you achieve that pardon.
God bless you." Thank you for those very
important questions and thank you for
your kind wishes, Spider. Um I never
worked with the Brazilian intelligence
service. I've always been told that they
are quite good, but they're very
regionally focused.
Um they do a lot of work against drugs,
which you would expect, um but they're
not players in the international
espionage scene. That's a good thing.
That's a good thing. Their their primary
goal is to keep Brazil and Brazilians
safe and secure.
That's the easy part of your question.
The hard part is
cyber.
Man,
this is this is a tough one. First of
all, I think what you do is absolutely
awesome. It's important, not even
important, it's critical for the safety
and security of government systems.
And hacking just isn't, you know,
hacking in and stealing somebody's
credit card information or social
security number. Hacking can be
taking down, you know, a hospital's
computer system, in which case people
can die. This happens all the time.
You know, hacking can be ruining
somebody's life by stealing their their
crypto or or, you know,
exposing their their identities, their
their inside personal information to to
people to be to be doxxed is another
example.
So, what you're doing is very important.
In terms of the ethics of the hacking
that that governments do, whether
they're contractors or intelligence
agents,
I struggle with this. You know, I went I
remember when hacking first became like
a mainstream thing. I'm going to say in
the late 1990s, very early 2000s, we did
some hacking
that I was aware of, I was briefed on,
and I remember my response being,
"That's really cool."
Well, you know,
when it ends up killing people,
that's not at all cool. When when the
worm or the program escapes that that
government's systems and goes out into
the world, that's not cool, either.
You know, if if you're if you're going
to hack into somebody's system,
this happened to me at the Senate
Foreign Relations Committee,
where I go to log on and my computer
just says "Yahoo!"
and then I have to dive under the desk
and yank the cord out from the wall.
Okay, that's a pain in the ass, but it's
not going to kill people.
Well, today's hacking actually
can kill people. And no, that's
ethically
that's not cool at all. Thanks for that
important question.
Hope Springs. Hey John, listening from
Canada. I have a question. What's your
favorite Greek dish or a national
treasure home-cooked food not many
people know about? Do you have a dish
you enjoy cooking for your loved ones?
Thanks for your service and I pray this
or a future president gives you the
pardon that you are so deserving of.
Thank you. Greetings from Canada. Thank
you very much.
Um
Wow, what's my favorite Greek dish? Man,
not only did I grow up in a 100% Greek
household,
but my mom
and my dad's mom and my dad's sister
and then later on my own sister
were all magnificent
cooks.
Magnificent.
So, we ate Greek food like
all the time. It was our family food.
I'm a pretty good cook.
And one of the things that I like to
make that my kids absolutely love
is um
something called um
soutzoukakia smyrneika.
They are football-shaped meatballs.
The recipe is originally from Smyrna,
which today is called Izmir
uh on the uh on the Turkish Aegean
coast.
Uh they're very heavy in garlic.
And I always make the tomato sauce that
goes with them
um
from scratch, my grandmother's recipe.
You can make similar ones that are
called
um
Yorvarlakia.
But instead of tomato sauce on top, they
have avgolemono soup, lemon egg rice
soup.
Which I could live on literally every
single day.
Um there are too many
favorite dishes to talk about. I I I
made this orzo dish the other day. You
know, I've had my I have my
grandmother's recipes on 3x5 cards.
Hundreds and hundreds of them. I'm going
to actually publish them privately
and give a book to my brother, a book to
my sister, a book to my each of my kids
and my nephews and nieces just so that
they have it. But um I made this orzo
dish with uh
with stewed tomatoes and my
grandmother's tomato sauce, but you also
add oregano, a lot of of oregano. Which
is cool because I had actually picked
the wild oregano
in a vacant lot across the street from
my house in Athens. When I was living in
Athens,
I noticed an old man in this vacant lot
across the house and I thought, "Oh,
this is surveillance." I pull a gun
and I go out there and I'm like, "Who
the are you and what do you want?"
And he's like, "What are you talking
about? I live three doors down and
there's wild asparagus growing here and
I'm just picking it to make an omelet
for breakfast."
And I was like, "Oh, oh, I'm sorry." I
put it back in my holster. I said, "I'm
sorry. I'm from the American Embassy and
I'm afraid of the 17 November." I said,
"I'm really sorry."
He's like, "No, no, it's okay. Relax."
He said, "I'm afraid of 17 November,
too. You know, they kill everybody." But
anyway, I said, "What are you doing?
You're looking for asparagus?" He said,
"Yeah, there's wild asparagus
growing all over this vacant lot."
Big corner lot directly across the
street from my house. I lived on a
corner lot.
And so he showed me the the asparagus.
So I picked some asparagus. And then he
says to me, "If you don't know, this is
oregano. It's wild oregano."
I went back
for days and picked oregano. So I filled
a jar like this big. That oregano lasted
me for 25 years.
I picked that oregano 26 years ago now
and I used the last of it a year ago.
It was so strong and perfect and
aromatic and delicious and wonderful
that you only needed a little of it.
And so
I'm proud of my Greek cooking.
I'm especially proud of my sister's
Greek cooking. My mom, unfortunately, is
is no longer with us. Neither is my
aunt. Certainly neither is my
grandmother, but they they taught us
well.
They did a great job.
Ty Higgins Tattoo says, "Much love from
Nashville. Thank you. I love Nashville.
Hope you get your pardon soon. Thank
you. I'm curious what you can recommend
for language learning." Oh, I love this
question.
I don't have access to the CIA language
program, but I've managed to learn
conversational Spanish and some Chinese
as well. That's awesome. And now I'm
interested in Arabic. What resources can
you recommend for the average guy to
boost his language learning skills? PS,
if you ever come to Nashville, I'll give
you a free tattoo. Thank you.
I know Greek Orthodox aren't big into
tattoos, but it's worth a shot. Tell you
the truth, I want to get one right here
on my arm
written in ancient Greek that says "Know
thyself."
Thank you for that.
This is such a great question and such
an important question. There are so many
wonderful programs and apps out there
right now. You know, back in the day
computer language programs
terrible.
But then Rosetta Stone came up around um
15 years ago and it was really good. And
then Duolingo
bettered
Rosetta Stone. I've used both.
Both are absolutely excellent. I think
Duolingo is probably a little bit better
in terms of pace.
But I'll tell you what, man, if you were
able to learn conversational Spanish and
and some Chinese, that tells me that you
have a facility for languages and you
will be able to pick up Arabic. It's
hard.
But I'll tell you the same thing my my
wonderful Arabic teacher, Ibrahim
Abdallah,
uh he told us.
He said there are 10 cases to every
um verb.
If you can learn 30 verbs
and understand the 10 cases,
you're going to speak Arabic.
Just 30 verbs and 10 forms,
I would recommend also, if you feel like
you need some one-on-one
to learn Arabic, and you might,
think of the local community college.
They charge practically nothing.
They use locals to teach the classes.
And there's nothing better in terms of
learning a language than conversing with
someone who's native in the language.
I I wish you the best of luck with this
because I think this is very important
and I think you're really seriously
doing the right thing.
So, folks, that's all we have time for
today. I want to thank you again. Thank
you. Thank you for subscribing, for
commenting, for liking, for sharing, for
talking about this podcast, and for
telling your friends and family about
it. We've grown by leaps and bounds and
it's only because of you. So, until next
time,
I'm John Kiriakou and this is Deep
Focus.
>> Mhm.